

Software Developer

wilson.ashai@gmail.com ashawilson.com linkedin.com/in/asha-i-wilson

Objective

I am a driven, full-stack software developer with 2 years of enterprise technology experience. I am always looking for opportunities to grow my technical and user experience skills in a product-focused, diverse and innovative environment inside and outside of work.

Experience

Associate Software Developer

Liberty Mutual Insurance, Boston, MA - Nov 2017 to Present

- Supporting and developing various global finance technology applications used internally by our global customers in Treasury, Reinsurance, and Accounting.
- Developed an accounting application that calculates the amortization schedule and journal entry values for all domestic and international corporate leases, totaling over \$1 billion in assets, using the newest accounting standards in Spring Boot, React and AWS's Aurora DB. Maintained 90% automated test coverage with tests written in Jest and Spock.
- Experience working on multiple applications from the start of the design process all the way through to production and devOps support.

Technology Associate, TechStart IT Development Program

Liberty Mutual Insurance, Boston, MA - Jan 2017 to Oct 2017

- Participated in a design thinking intensive with teammates to strategize a solution for legal data analysts that could help alleviate the data knowledge gap between novice and expert users.
- Created relevant user interviews, mockups/wireframes, and user personas based on our design research.
- Collaborated with teammates to deliver a production environment MVP web app that allows analysts to create, edit, and search legal metadata in just ten weeks, built using Node, Angular 2, Gulp, and MySQL.

Volunteer Work

Events and Volunteer Lead, Black Girls Code (Boston Chapter)

Nov 2018 to Present

- Assist with event logistics for our quarterly workshops, such as the Sphero Robotics Seminar, Game Jam, Microsoft MakeCode Arcade.
- Facilitate and lead volunteer training sessions before each workshop.
- Communicate with past volunteers about all future programs and volunteer opportunities.

Volunteer, Day of Code at Charlestown High School - Dec 2017, Nov 2018

Education

University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, PA – BS in Information Science, May 2016

Cum laude. University scholarship awardee. Member of WiCS (Women in Computer Science).

Skills

Backend Java (Spring Boot), Node, Python 2 & 3, Spock, RESTful API

Frontend JavaScript (ES6, Typescript), React (Redux, MobX), Angular 2, Jest, CSS/HTML

Design Adobe InDesign Illustrator + XD, Balsamiq, Design Thinking, InVision

Other MySQL, Git, Subversion, Agile (Scrum, Kanban), Netlify